# CLINT JASON NGASSA YEPGWA

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

ngassajason@gmail.com

https://clintjason.com/

SPOKEN LANGUAGE:

ENGLISH | FRENCH - NATIVE

**CURRENT LOCATION: CAMEROON** 

AVAILABLE TO RELOCATE: EUROPE

I am a passionate, independent, and responsible web developer, who is effective at developing web solutions designed according to company brand and objectives. Ready to bring over 5 years of related experience to a growth-oriented team.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

#### CJ Group Ltd

January 2022 to present

- 1. He designed and built a Full-stack application with the MEVM stack for an online financial education and coaching website for a client. Setup online booking, newsletter management, CMS with simple and useful UI, and subscription management.
- 2. As Tech lead, he daily communicated with employees, assigned roles, raised issues on Gitlab, helped fellow colleagues, redefined feature priorities, supervised project evolution, setup meetups and assist colleagues in onboarding project.

- 3. As Tech lead, he continually insisted on component development best practices to support application future growth on the strength of scalable, maintainable and testable Coding styles.
- 4. Working in an Agile-driven environment, He effectively used the agile methodology of the SDLC to respect project timelines and stick to available resources.
- 5. As a developer, he continually provided maintenance of current web apps and bug fixes for existing web app bugs.
- 6. He developed and updated designs to meet specific usability, accessibility, and performance requirements such as quick-loading sites with particular layouts for an outstanding UX.
- 7. He coordinated with client to finalize designs and confirm requirements.

#### WEB DEVELOPER MENTOR

## **OpenClassrooms**

February 2019 to April 2023

- 1. He Mentors aspiring Web Developers in French and English Languages for over 3 years in the web developer, web integrator, and junior web developer paths for both French and English paths.
- 2. He has mentored over 130 students successfully in more than 3 years with and average rating of 4.8 stars on 5 stars.
- 3. Interacts daily with students with rich Oral and written communication skills.
- 4. He is Patient and understanding with every student tailoring the mentoring process according to student personal makeup.
- 5. He inspires them by his passion for development and his culture of excellence leading them to be better developers.

- 6. He regularly proofs himself reliable and efficient in resolving all their challenges related to their code and projects. These is showed by his average student rating of 4.8 on 5 stars.
- Building a house rental website and a restaurant mobile-first website with HTML5, CSS3, and SASS, he demonstrated mastery in building responsive mobile-first websites and the use of these tech stacks.
- 8. He built a full fledge website powered with JS to interact with a backend API revealing a good understanding of the REST infrastructure and a good use of JS and asynchronous request.
- 9. Demonstrated good understanding and use of SEO best practices, and Web accessibility principles by improving the SEO and accessibility of an existing website.
- 10. Built full fledge backend API with NodeJS, Express, and MongoDB to interact with an AngularJS Frontend. This demonstrated his ability to build backend APIs with the tech stack.
- He built a Full Stack application with the MEVN and the MERN stacks for a social media platform demonstrating full operational knowledge of building full stack applications.
- Regular use and debugging of SQL and NoSQL databases like MySQL, MongoDB for databases in full-stack projects.
- 13. Debugged and assisted students to build WordPress websites from scratch.
- 14. He Built websites and CMS with OOP PHP, HTML5 & CSS3.
- Regularly used OOP principles to build JS Carousels, and JS powered frontend websites.
- Tutoring and mentoring students in these stacks, he has demonstrated proven strong Proficiency in HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, VueJS, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, SQL and NOSQL, GIT.

# **Frontend Developer**

#### Freelance

2019 to 2020

- 1. He Developed a housing rental website with WordPress and Improved SEO results so much that the website competed with airbnb on the first page of major search engines results. During the time he maintained the website SEO, it's SEO ranking didn't go below the first page for a year.
- 2. He built a mobile-first website (gosahc) for a local clinic from scratch with HTML5, CSS3, JS, and PHP, applied several relevant security features to the website and made it SEO friendly.
- 3. He completely designed and built a mobile-first responsive WordPress website (Planbpassports) for a client dealing with passports in islands and the user was highly satisfied.
- 4. He refurbished and existing website, optimizing it for performance, accessibility, and the look and feel of the website (https://igraphix237.com/).
- 5. Used ReactJS-Redux, JavaScript, CSS3 and HTML5 to build linguistic website front view.
- 6. Regularly performed UI Improvements and platform maintenance on both the linguistic CMS and the website.
- 7. Built front-end for Mobile-first following SEO and Accessibility best practices.
- 8. Required patience and good Communication skills to interact with client with constantly changing requirements.
- 9. Designed and built a mobile-first responsive linguistic French localization CV website from scratch with WordPress and several plugins.

# Frontend Developer | Software Engineer

## Adipster Tech Ltd

August 2018 to February 2019

- 1. Achieved a unit test coverage of the frontend web app using jest.
- 2. Regularly maintained and added new features to existing web app.
- 3. Analyzed user needs and proposed designs to meet them.
- 4. Comfortable working with REST API's infrastructure between the Front and Back.
- 5. Monitored and improved internal software processes.
- 6. Helped in conflict resolution among team members.
- 7. Mentored interns and new colleagues in the onboarding process.
- 8. Supported the software development and testing processes. Monitoring and improving on the software internal processes.

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

#### IT kamer Ltd

September 2016 to February 2017

- 1. Development of web scraping tool with python.
- 2. Development of a Barcode Scanner Android Application to scan barcodes using android, Java, and PHP.
- 3. Development of frontend for a school management system with HTML5, CSS3, JQUERY, JS and other libraries.
- 4. Interacted with client to produce the various SDLC documents with the requirements document, produce the system analysis document and other documents according to needs.

- 5.Embraced creativity to decide what User interfaces to use and prototye for school management system.
- 6. Responsible for creating wireframes for the website development.
- 7. Report writing and regular production of software procedure documents.
- 8. Performed negotiations with potential clients to determine / increase pay of work.
- 9. Provide technical support and maintenance whenever needed by colleagues.

# **EDUCATION**

# M.Eng in Software Engineering

**University Of Buea** 2020

- 1. Designed and built a machine learning model for the prediction of 5 recurrent tropical diseases based on a dataset of patient medical record and symptoms analysis.
- Designed and built a machine learning model for the prediction of the demographic spread of tropical diseases based on patient medical record and symptom analysis over a specific period and tropical region.
- 3. Built Fullstack Application with React-Redux-Flask to interface Machine Learning Model

# **B.Eng in Software Engineering**

## **University Of Buea** 2017

- 1. Built a prototype e-learning platform to illustrate online education.
- 2. Mastered programming fundamentals and OOP for programming languages.
- 3. Mastered the SDLC.
- 4. Experienced Coding with C, Java, android, Python, PHP, JavaScript, AngularJs, WordPress, CSS3 and HTML5.
- 5. Experienced the use of git version control systems, Gitlab, and GitBucket.
- 6. Experienced using Kanban tools like Trello.

## **SKILLS**

- PYTHON | PHP | NODEJS
- EXPRESS JS | FLASK | ADONIS
- FRONT END HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | JS | JQUERY (7 YEARS)
- WORDPRESS | WIX | KIRBY | WEBFLOW
- REACT JS | REDUX
- VUE JS | VUEX | VUE TESTING TOOLS | JEST
- POSTGRESQL | SQLITE | MYSQL | MARIADB | MONGODB
- GIT | GITLAB | HEROKU | AWS LIGHTSAIL
- BLOCKCHAIN | MACHINE LEARNING | DATA SCIENCE
- BOOTSTRAP | MARERIAL UI
- PHOTOSHOP | LIGHTROOM | FIGMA

# **CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES**

Interactivity with JavaScript University of Michigan on Coursera						
Present						
Introduction to R						
June 2010 to Present						

# **Introduction to CSS3**

June 2019 to Present

#### **Create Web Page Layouts With CSS**

November 2019 to Present

## **Drive Traffic to Your Website With Search Engine Optimization (SEO)**

December 2019 to Present

Introduction to Git for Data Science August 2019 to Present	
Introduction to Python June 2019 to Present	
Intro to SQL for Data Science	
July 2019 to Present	
Learn How to Learn	
July 2019 to Present	
Manage Your Code Project With Git & Github	
September 2019 to Present	
Produce Maintainable CSS With Sass	
September 2019 to Present	
Understanding the Web	
July 2019 to Present	

December 2019 to Present